Guide to the Texas Jewish Historical Society Collection, 1999-2022 MS 1041
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Texas Jewish Historical Society Collection
1999-2022
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Texas Jewish Historical Society; Furman, Joshua, Dr.
MS 1041
.50 Linear Feet 1 box
Two boxes containing Texas Jewish Historical Society Newsletters, membership directories, and a brochure document some events and activities undertaken by the Texas Jewish Historical Society from 1999 to present.
Biographical / Historical
In 1980 Rabbi Jimmy Kessler of Galveston published letters in The Jewish Herald-Voice of Houston and in The Texas Jewish Post of Dallas/Fort Worth calling for the creation of a historical society to preserve the history of the Texas Jewish experience. As a result, in March 1980 a first Gathering of interested Texans took place in San Antonio to organize the Texas Jewish Historical Society, with Rabbi Kessler as its first president. Today, the Texas Jewish Historical Society has over 550 members. Since its founding, the TJHS has sponsored and encouraged research, publications, and projects on Texas Jewish history, providing a forum for scholars, students, journalists, and genealogists.
excerpted from: https://txjhs.org/history-of-tjhs/
Content Description
Texas Jewish Historical Society Newsletters, membership directories, and a brochure document some events and activities undertaken by the Texas Jewish Historical Society from 1999 to present.
Forms part of the Houston Jewish History Archive.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials donated by Dr. Joshua Furman in August 2022.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in three series:
Series I: Membership Directories; Series II: Newsletters; Series III: Promotional Materials
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
newsletters; directories; brochures
Subjects (Persons)
Furman, Joshua, Dr.
- Series I: Membership Directories
  - TJHS membership directory, 2010-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - TJHS membership directory (2), 2018-2020 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Newsletters
  - TJHS newsletters, 1999-01-2004-04 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - TJHS newsletters, Summer 2004-August 2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - TJHS newsletters, 2008-11-2014-12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - TJHS newsletter, 2016-07-2020-09 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - TJHS newsletters, 2021-03-2022-08 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series III: Promotional Materials
  - TJHS brochure, 2019 (Box 1)